Paul Abelson Papers 5192
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Motion Picture Arbitration Cases, 1939-1941 (Box 51, Folder 2)
- Motion Picture Agreements, 1935-1939 (Box 51, Folder 3)
- Muff Bed Correspondence, 1914-1918 (Box 51, Folder 4)
- Muff Bed Correspondence, 1914-1918 (Box 51, Folder 5)
- Muff Bed Agreements, 1914-1917 (Box 51, Folder 6)
- Painting and Decorating Industry (Box 51, Folder 7)
- Paper Box Industry (Box 51, Folder 8)
- Retail Stores Industry (Box 51, Folder 9)
- Restaurant Industry (Box 51, Folder 10)
- Shoe Industry (Box 51, Folder 11)
- Underwear Industry (Box 51, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous decisions, 1914-1919 (Box 51, Folder 13)
- Abelson's correspondence to Louis D. Brandeis, 1937 (Box 52, Folder 1)
- Abelson's Correspondence with Max and Arthur Meyer, 1935-1940 (Box 52, Folder 2)
- Abelson's Correspondence with Joel Seidman re Seidman's mss. of book, "Labor in the Needle Trades", 1941 (Box 52, Folder 3)
- Abelson's Correspondence with Ralph T. Seward re serving as War Labor Board mediator (Box 52, Folder 4)
- Abelson's Correspondence as Secretary of Council of Moderators, 1913-1916 (Box 52, Folder 5)
- Abelson - Interview with Professor Jesse T. Carpenter (Box 52, Folder 6)
- Abelson - Lectures, Cornell University, "Climate of Opinion", 1949 (Box 52, Folder 7)
- Abelson - Lectures, Cornell University, "Climate of Opinion", 1949 (Box 52, Folder 8)
- "Origins of Protocol" (Box 52, Folder 9)
- "Dress" (Box 52, Folder 10)
- "Men's" (Box 52, Folder 11)
- "Furs" (Box 52, Folder 12)
- "Millinery" (Box 52, Folder 13)
- "Men's Hats" (Box 52, Folder 14)
- "Impartial Chairman" (Box 52, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous (Box 52, Folder 16)
- Abelson - Lecture - NIC High School, 1939 (Box 52, Folder 17)
- Abelson - Lecture - Outlines (Box 52, Folder 18)
- Abelson - Lecture - Notes, 1950 (Box 52, Folder 19)
- Abelson - Miscellaneous (Box 52, Folder 20)
- Abelson, Secretary of Tenement House Committee, 1903-1904 (Box 52, Folder 21)
- American Arbitration Association, 1941-1943 (Box 52, Folder 22)
  publications, memos, correspondence, reports, notes, legal documents
- American Federation of Labor, 1928 (Box 52, Folder 23)
- Arbitrator's - Code of Ethics, 1949-1950 (Box 52, Folder 24)
- Atlantic and Gulf Ship Operators Association (Box 52, Folder 25)
- Board of Grievances, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1911-1913 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  Contains minutes of minutes, "Intensive Study of The Records of the Board of Grievances," chart
- Board of Grievances, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1911-1913 (Box 53, Folder 2)
- Board of Grievances, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1911-1913 (Box 53, Folder 3)
- Board of Grievances, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1911-1913 (Box 53, Folder 4)
- Board of Grievances, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1911-1913 (Box 53, Folder 5)
- Board of Grievances, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1911-1913 (Box 53, Folder 6)
- Board of Grievances, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1911-1913 (Box 53, Folder 7)
- Board of Grievances, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1911-1913 (Box 53, Folder 8)
- Board of Grievances, Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry, 1911-1913 (Box 53, Folder 9)
- Joint Meeting of the Grievance Board and the Wage Scale Board of the Dress and Waist Industry, 1913 (Box 53, Folder 10)
- Boston Ladies Garment Manufacturers Association, Speeches at an informal dinner, 1913 (Box 54, Folder 1)
- Brewery workers, agreement with explanations, 1947 (Box 54, Folder 2)
- Brookwood Labor College, Course outlines, 1923-1928 (Box 54, Folder 3)
- Building Trades, government hearings, wage schedule, 1947 (Box 54, Folder 4)
- Bureau of Industry, Jewish Community - notes, memo, 1918 (Box 54, Folder 5)
- Cleaning and Dyeing Industry, N.Y.S. Wage Board, 1938-1939 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  Minutes, report, publications, correspondence, charts
- Cleaning and Dyeing Industry, N.Y.S. Wage Board, 1938-1939 (Box 54, Folder 7)
- Cleaning and Dyeing Industry, N.Y.S. Wage Board, 1938-1939 (Box 54, Folder 8)
- Cleaning and Dyeing Industry, N.Y.S. Wage Board, 1938-1939 (Box 54, Folder 9)
- Cleveland Garment Factories, 1921 (Box 54, Folder 10)
- Cloak and Suit Industry, Governor's Advisory Committee, reports, brief, recommendations, 1913-1926 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  "Grievance Machinery in the Women's Cloak and Suit Industry, Contributions" by Dr. Paul Abelson, "The Protocol and the Union," address by John A. Dyche
- Cloak and Suit Industry, Governor's Advisory Committee, reports, brief, recommendations, 1913-1926 (Box 54, Folder 12)
- Cloak and Suit Industry, Governor's Advisory Committee, reports, brief, recommendations, 1913-1926 (Box 54, Folder 13)
- Clothing Industry (Box 54, Folder 14)
- Clothing Trades Commission, correspondence, 1914 (Box 54, Folder 15)
- Coat and Suit Industry, Recovery Board, 1936-1950 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  Memos, documents, reports, corres., certificates, announcements
- Coat and Suit Industry, Recovery Board, 1936-1950 (Box 55, Folder 2)
- Coat and Suit Industry, Recovery Board, 1936-1950 (Box 55, Folder 3)
- Coat and Suit Industry, Recovery Board, 1936-1950 (Box 55, Folder 4)
- Coat and Suit Industry, Recovery Board, 1936-1950 (Box 55, Folder 5)
- Coat and Suit Industry, Recovery Board, 1936-1950 (Box 55, Folder 6)
- Coat and Suit Industry, Recovery Board, 1936-1950 (Box 55, Folder 7)
- Coat and Suit Industry, Recovery Board, 1936-1950 (Box 55, Folder 8)
- Coat and Suit Industry, Recovery Board, 1936-1950 (Box 55, Folder 9)
- Conference for Cheaper Kosher Meat, 1902-1913 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  clippings, broadsides, handwritten notes, statements issued by Executive Committee of the Conference
- Discrimination, chart, 1913 (Box 55, Folder 11)
- Douglas, Paul - clipping, charts, 1925 (Box 55, Folder 12)
- Editorials - typed copies of articles published, 1912-1913 (Box 55, Folder 13)
- Educational Alliance, Department of Adult Immigrants (Box 56, Folder 1)
  list of words to be used in class work
- Employers Organizations, articles (Box 56, Folder 2)
- Federal Trade Commission, releases, dockets, 1936-1941 (Box 56, Folder 3)
- Fur & Leather Workers, "Outline of the History of the International Fur and Leather Workers Union", 1949 (Box 56, Folder 4)
- Harbor Carriers of the Port of NY, Issues of Bulletin, 1947 (Box 56, Folder 5)
- Ingersall, Raymond V., speech, outline, 1931 (Box 56, Folder 6)
- Journal of Commerce, correspondence, 1948 (Box 56, Folder 7)
- Kehillah, Jewish Community - reports, correspondence, 1910-1918 (Box 56, Folder 8)
- Kehillah, Jewish Community - reports, correspondence, 1910-1918 (Box 56, Folder 9)
- Klein, Julius - address, 1931 (Box 56, Folder 10)
- Legislation - legislative bills (Box 56, Folder 11)
- Louisiana - notorized statements of employees of Libbey-Qwens-Ford Glass Co. in Shreveport, La., 1946 (Box 56, Folder 12)
- Mayer, Henry - "The Closed Shop Issue", 1941 (Box 56, Folder 13)
- Meat Trade Institute - 2 issues of "Labor Bulletin", 1947 (Box 56, Folder 14)
- Merritt, Gordon - Introductory Statement by Merritt Before Gwinn Sub-Committee of the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives (Box 56, Folder 15)
- Milk Industry - articles, memos, publications, opinion, 1965 (Box 56, Folder 16)
- Millinery Industry - article, case adjustments, 1915-1916 (Box 56, Folder 17)
- Minimum Wage Boards - Beauty Shop, Cleaning and Dyeing, Confectionery, Hotel and Restaurant, and Laundry Industries - reports, 1935-1939 (Box 56, Folder 18)
- Minimum Wage Boards - Beauty Shop, Cleaning and Dyeing, Confectionery, Hotel and Restaurant, and Laundry Industries - reports, 1935-1939 (Box 56, Folder 19)
- Minimum Wage Boards - Beauty Shop, Cleaning and Dyeing, Confectionery, Hotel and Restaurant, and Laundry Industries - reports, 1935-1939 (Box 56, Folder 20)
- Minimum Wage Boards - Beauty Shop, Cleaning and Dyeing, Confectionery, Hotel and Restaurant, and Laundry Industries - reports, 1935-1939 (Box 56, Folder 21)
- Minimum Wage Boards - Beauty Shop, Cleaning and Dyeing, Confectionery, Hotel and Restaurant, and Laundry Industries - reports, 1935-1939 (Box 56, Folder 22)
- Minimum Wage Boards - Beauty Shop, Cleaning and Dyeing, Confectionery, Hotel and Restaurant, and Laundry Industries - reports, 1935-1939 (Box 56, Folder 23)
- Municipal Committee for the Relief of Home Owners - publications, 1936 (Box 56, Folder 24)
- National Academy of Arbitrators, 1938-1953 (Box 56a, Folder 1)
  form letters, correspondence, lists of members, minutes, programs
- National Academy of Arbitrators, 1938-1953 (Box 56a, Folder 2)
- National Child Labor Committee - single issue of "American Child", 1953 (Box 56a, Folder 3)
- National Industrial Recovery Administration (NIRA) - Hearings, Fur Industry, Hearing Transcripts, 1934 (Box 57, Folder 1)
- National Industrial Recovery Administration (NIRA) - Hearings, Fur Industry, Hearing Transcripts, 1934 (Box 58, Folder 1)
- National Labor Relations Board Releases, NIRA - Hearing Transcripts, Millinery Industry, 1934-1936 (Box 59, Folder 1)
- National Labor Relations Board Releases, NIRA - Hearing Transcripts, Millinery Industry, 1934-1936 (Box 60, Folder 1)
- National Labor Relations Board Releases, NIRA - Hearing Transcripts, Millinery Industry, 1934-1936 (Box 61, Folder 1)
- National Labor Relations Board Releases, NIRA - Hearing Transcripts, Millinery Industry, 1934-1936 (Box 62, Folder 1)
- National Recovery Administration, Addresses, 1935 (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Administrative Orders, printed sheets, 1934-1935 (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Apprentice Training, 1934 (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Code Authority (CA) Blouse and Skirt Industry, 1934-1935 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  printed regulations, correspondence, pamphlet. newsletter, telegrams
- CA- Cap and Cloth Hat Manufacturing Industry, 1929-1934 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  correspondence, speech by I.H. Goldberg
- CA- Coat and Suit Industry, 1935-1951 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  publications, newsletter, form letter
- CA- Fur Industry- Code of Fair Competition (Box 63, Folder 7)
- CA- Fur Industry - Conference Committee Statement, notes, conference minutes, 1912-1936 (Box 63, Folder 8)
- CA- Fur Industry - Fact Finding Commissions Notes, charts, questionnaires, 1933-1934 (Box 63, Folder 9)
- CA- Fur Industry - Hatters' Fur Cutting, Correspondence, 1934 (Box 63, Folder 10)
- CA- Fur Industry - Hearing notices, proposed code, reports, 1933-1935 (Box 63, Folder 11)
- CA-Fur Industry - List of petitioners, charts, correspondence, 1934 (Box 64, Folder 1)
- CA-Fur Industry - Miscellaneous documents (Box 64, Folder 2)
- CA-Fur Industry - Miscellaneous documents (Box 64, Folder 3)
- CA-Fur Industry - Organization-proposed code, correspondence, questionnaire, 1935 (Box 64, Folder 4)
- CA-Fur Industry - Special Fur Commission, publications, reports, recommendations, correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 64, Folder 5)
- CA-Fur Industry - Special Fur Commission, publications, reports, recommendations, correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 64, Folder 6)
- CA-Fur Industry, clippings (Box 64, Folder 7)
- CA-General - Budget information, releases, publications, report, correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 64, Folder 8)
- CA-Hat Industry - notices of hearings, by-laws, correspondence, statistical reports, 1934 (Box 65, Folder 1)
- CA-Infant's and Children's Wear Industry -Organization chart, publication, correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 65, Folder 2)
- CA-Lumber Industry - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 65, Folder 3)
- CA-Men's Clothing Industry - Code of fair competition, 1933 (Box 65, Folder 4)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Administrative Orders, publications, reports, hearing, 1934 (Box 65, Folder 5)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Administrative Orders, publications, reports, hearing, 1934 (Box 65, Folder 6)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Administrative Orders, publications, reports, hearing, 1934 (Box 65, Folder 7)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Administrative Orders, publications, reports, hearing, 1934 (Box 65, Folder 8)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Proceedings, correspondence, reports hearings, 1933-1935 (Box 66, Folder 1)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Proceedings, correspondence, reports hearings, 1933-1935 (Box 66, Folder 2)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Proceedings, correspondence, reports hearings, 1933-1935 (Box 66, Folder 3)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Proceedings, correspondence, reports hearings, 1933-1935 (Box 66, Folder 4)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Proceedings, correspondence, reports hearings, 1933-1935 (Box 66, Folder 5)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Minutes, handbook, budgets, correspondence, 1933-1935 (Box 67, Folder 1)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Minutes, handbook, budgets, correspondence, 1933-1935 (Box 67, Folder 2)
- CA-Millinery Industry - Minutes, handbook, budgets, correspondence, 1933-1935 (Box 67, Folder 3)
- CA-Undergarment & Negligee Industry - correspondence, survey, orders, forms, 1934-1935 (Box 67, Folder 4)
- Executive orders, printed, 1933-1935 (Box 68, Folder 1)
- Executive orders, printed, 1933-1935 (Box 68, Folder 2)
- "Handbook of NBA Information" (Box 68, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous, 1933-1936 (Box 68, Folder 4)
- Offices memos and orders, 1934-1935 (Box 68, Folder 5)
- Releases, announcements, 1933-1934 (Box 68, Folder 6)
- Reports, 1935 (Box 68, Folder 7)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 68, Folder 8)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 68, Folder 9)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 68, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous NRA documents and related papers re questionnaires (Box 69, Folder 1)
- National War Labor Board, 1944 (Box 70, Folder 1)
- Needlecraft Educational Commission, organizational chart (Box 70, Folder 2)
- NIC Board of Education, programs, 1936-1953 (Box 70, Folder 3)
- NY Clothing Manufacturers Exchange, Inc., program, 1929 (Box 70, Folder 4)
- NY Hotel Trades Council, announcement (Box 70, Folder 5)
- NYS Board of Mediation, 1914-1948 (Box 70, Folder 6)
- NYS Factory Investigating Commission, form letter, 1914 (Box 70, Folder 7)
- NYS Labor Relations Board, decisions, 1946-1948 (Box 70, Folder 8)
- New Zealand, correspondence, 1913 (Box 70, Folder 9)
- Orphy, H.A. "An Analysis of Welfare Programmes in Egyptian Industry - A Tobacco Factory Case Study" (Box 70, Folder 10)
- Pocketbook Workers - program, 1948 (Box 70, Folder 11)
- Protocol - "The Protocol" by John E. Williams and related documents, 1915-1931 (Box 70, Folder 12)
- Radio Officer's Union - releases, form letters, 1947-1948 (Box 70, Folder 13)
- Realty Advisory Board - issue of "Bulletin," release, publications, awards, 1944-1947 (Box 70, Folder 14)
- Shoe Industry - Brief and program, 1948 (Box 70, Folder 15)
- Silk Industry - regulations, demands, notes, clippings, petition, 1912-1913 (Box 70, Folder 16)
- Strikes - articles, 1926 (Box 70, Folder 17)
- Tariff Board - notes, correspondence, schedules, forms, 1911 (Box 70, Folder 18)
- Teamsters - form letters, 1948-1949 (Box 70, Folder 19)
- Toy Manufacturers - single issue "Bulletin", 1946 (Box 70, Folder 20)
- Unemployment - report, "What Have We Learned About Unemployment," by Jacob Billikopf (Box 70, Folder 21)
- United Cloth Hat & Cap Makers, 1921 (Box 70, Folder 22)
- Voluntary Arbitration - correspondence, article, 1951 (Box 70, Folder 23)
- Articles and reprints (Box 71, Folder 1)
- Alger, George W., 1931-1935 (Box 72, Folder 1)
- Barnes, Charles B., 1920-1929 (Box 72, Folder 2)
- Barnes, Charles B., 1920-1929 (Box 72, Folder 3)
- Barnes, Charles B., 1920-1929 (Box 72, Folder 4)
- Eastrin, 1934 (Box 72, Folder 5)
- Feldblum, A., 1933-1934 (Box 72, Folder 6)
- Feldblum, A., 1933-1934 (Box 72, Folder 7)
- Feldblum, A., 1935-1936 (Box 73, Folder 1)
- Feldblum, A., 1935-1936 (Box 73, Folder 2)
- Ingersoll, Raymond V., 1924-1926 (Box 73, Folder 3)
- Ingersoll, Raymond V., 1924-1926 (Box 73, Folder 4)
- Mack, Julian W., 1916 (Box 74, Folder 1)
- Moskowitz, Henry, 1929-1936 (Box 74, Folder 2)
- Moskowitz, Henry, 1929-1936 (Box 74, Folder 3)
- Moskowitz, Henry, 1929-1936 (Box 74, Folder 4)
- Rogers, Lindsay, 1931 (Box 74, Folder 5)
- Rosenblatt, Sol A., 1935-1938 (Box 74, Folder 6)
- Rosenblatt, Sol A., 1935-1938 (Box 74, Folder 7)
- Rosenblatt, Sol A., 1939-1949 (Box 75, Folder 1)
- Rosenblatt, Sol A., 1939-1949 (Box 75, Folder 2)
- Rosenblatt, Sol A., 1939-1949 (Box 75, Folder 3)
- Rosenblatt, Sol A., 1939-1949 (Box 75, Folder 4)
- Taylor, George W., 1931-1934 (Box 75, Folder 5)
- Taylor, George W., 1931-1934 (Box 75, Folder 6)
- Taylor, George W., 1934-1939 (Box 76, Folder 1)
- Taylor, George W., 1934-1939 (Box 76, Folder 2)
- Taylor, George W., 1934-1939 (Box 76, Folder 3)
- Taylor, George W., 1934-1939 (Box 76, Folder 4)
- Taylor, George W., 1934-1939 (Box 76, Folder 5)
- Walker, James J., 1940-46 (Box 77, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous (Box 78, Folder 1)
  addresses, notes, photographs of Paul Abelson, membership cards, time book, reports
- Newspaper clippings (Box 79, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 80, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 81, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 82, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 83, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 84, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 85, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 86, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 87, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 88, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 89, Folder 1)
- Documents and clippings (Box 90, Folder 1)
- Documents and clippings (Box 91, Folder 1)